<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
    <!-- ==================== MAIN MENU ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_menu_ab">
        <text>AlifeBalance</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== TAB NAMES ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_menu_smart_balance">
        <text>Smart Balance</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_menu_inventory_balance">
        <text>Inventory Balance</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_menu_development">
        <text>Development</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== SHARED ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_title">
        <text>AlifeBalance</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== SMART BALANCE TAB ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_desc">
        <text>Combat thins the Zone faster than the engine refills it. AlifeBalance tracks deaths per (level, faction) and advances the respawn cooldown of an eligible smart on that level by a fraction of its cooldown each advance. After the configured number of advances the cooldown expires and the engine spawns one squad from the smart's own configured pool on its next alife tick. It does not spawn anything itself. Works alongside vanilla, ZCP, Redone, and any other spawner mod.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_enabled">
        <text>Enable Smart Balance</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_enabled_desc">
        <text>Master toggle for Smart Balance. When off, no death tracking and no cooldown advances.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_advances">
        <text>Advances to floor</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_advances_desc">
        <text>How many advances it takes to drive one smart from full cooldown to the min_minutes floor. One advance fires when a squad's worth of deaths (the threshold) has accumulated for a (level, faction) pair, and subtracts 1/advances of the smart's cooldown. AlifeBalance does not spawn anything; once the smart's cooldown is at the floor, the engine's own clock ages out the rest and the engine's try_respawn fires its normal spawn. At 1, one threshold puts a smart at the floor in one advance. At 4 (default), four thresholds drive a smart through, 25% per advance. At 8, eight thresholds, 12.5% per advance. Higher values pace the acceleration across more sustained combat.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_min_minutes">
        <text>Minimum cooldown remaining (game minutes)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_min_minutes_desc">
        <text>Minimum cooldown that must remain on a smart after an advance applies, in game minutes. AlifeBalance never pushes the cooldown below this floor; the engine's own clock ages out the last leg naturally and fires the spawn from there. A smart already at or below this floor is skipped on the next advance (counter holds for next tick). Default 120 minutes (two game hours). Raise to leave more natural cooldown after every advance.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== INVENTORY BALANCE TAB ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_inventory_balance_desc">
        <text>Vanilla NPC looting costs two things over long sessions: a long-lived stalker carries a small shop of gear so killing them is a jackpot, and every looted item is a server object that pushes saves toward the 65535 engine cap (vanilla Anomaly warns at 64000 via alife_on_limit). Anti-loot addons (NPC Stop Looting Dead Bodies, Weapons Drop on Bodies, BoltBeGone) handle this by blocking or rewriting the loot path. Inventory Balance fixes the cause: a periodic scanner walks online stalkers in small batches and releases anything above the per-category ceiling from configs/alifebalance/ab_inventory_policy.ltx. Each NPC is rescanned at most once per game-day. Only random long-lived stalkers (gulag survivors, patrols) are scanned. Companions, story NPCs, traders, and named characters are skipped at the scheduler. Ceilings are DLTX-overridable.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_inventory_balance_enabled_inventory">
        <text>Enable Inventory Balance</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_inventory_balance_enabled_inventory_desc">
        <text>Periodic scanner that bounds NPC inventory hoarding so anti-loot addons are no longer needed. Each online stalker is rescanned at most once per game-day. The scanner walks the eligible set in small batches spread across frames. Per-category max ceilings loaded from configs/alifebalance/ab_inventory_policy.ltx. Anything above the max is released. Covers equipped-slot ammo (in rounds), grenades, consumables (medkit / bandage / antirad / stim / pill / food / drink), and gear (weapons / outfits / helmets / artefacts / crafting / device). DLTX-overridable. Only random long-lived stalkers (gulag survivors, patrols) are scanned. Companions, story NPCs, traders, and named characters are skipped at the scheduler. Quest items, equipped gear, runtime-story_id items, companion-gifted items, and player-strapped weapons are pre-filtered by xinventory and never touched. When off, vanilla trim applies and online inventories accumulate without bound.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_inventory_balance_npcs_per_frame">
        <text>NPCs per frame</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_inventory_balance_npcs_per_frame_desc">
        <text>How many NPCs the scanner trims in a single frame. 1 keeps every frame cheap (one inventory walk per frame). Raise only if the scanner cannot keep up with the eligible set on very large saves. The per-NPC cooldown already paces work across long stretches of game-time.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_inventory_balance_scan_cooldown_h">
        <text>Per-NPC rescan cooldown (game hours)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_inventory_balance_scan_cooldown_h_desc">
        <text>An NPC is not rescanned until this many game-hours have elapsed since its last scan. Default 24 (one game-day). Lower values trim more often (more aggressive against fast hoarders). Higher values reduce overall work and let NPCs hold modest loot longer. This cooldown is the rate limit on the whole feature.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== DEVELOPMENT TAB ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_desc">
        <text>Debug and development tools. DEBUG level enables structured tracing of every advance to alifebalance.log. Has performance cost.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Development - Logging -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_hdr_logging">
        <text>Logging</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_log_level">
        <text>Log level</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_log_level_desc">
        <text>Controls log verbosity. ERROR: crashes only. WARN: anomalies. INFO: startup and config only. DEBUG: every death, advance, eligible-set compute, gate outcome, and tick summary.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_error">
        <text>Error</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_warn">
        <text>Warn</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_info">
        <text>Info</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_debug">
        <text>Debug</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Development - Diagnostics -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_hdr_diagnostics">
        <text>Diagnostics</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_show_markers">
        <text>Show map markers</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_show_markers_desc">
        <text>Place a green PDA map marker on every smart terrain that receives an advance. The marker lingers for 5 real-time minutes, then clears. Right-click any marker to teleport to that smart or show its stats. Independent of log level.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_btn_show_status">
        <text>Show status</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_btn_show_status_desc">
        <text>Display total deaths, counted deaths (faction + level resolved), trash-tier filtered, scan ticks, advances fired, and engine spawns observed.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_btn_reset_counters">
        <text>Reset counters</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_btn_reset_counters_desc">
        <text>Clear all death counters, eligibility and threshold caches, per-smart advance stats, and diagnostic counters. Existing cooldown advances already written to smart-terrain timestamps persist. The engine resolves them on its next try_respawn.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Map menu actions -->
    <string id="st_ab_smart_map_teleport_to">
        <text>Teleport to</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_ab_smart_map_show_stats">
        <text>Show stats for</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
