<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
    <!-- ==================== MAIN MENU ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_menu_ab">
        <text>AlifeBalance</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== TAB NAMES ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_menu_smart_balance">
        <text>Smart Balance</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_menu_development">
        <text>Development</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== SHARED ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_title">
        <text>AlifeBalance</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== SMART BALANCE TAB ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_desc">
        <text>Smart Balance keeps each map's population near what the map itself declares. It regularly counts who is actually alive, per faction, with all mutants as one group. Wiped-out groups come back sooner and their depleted squads are gradually refilled; overgrown groups wait longer. Corrections pick their targets: only smart terrains that can spawn the depleted group and still have spawn room, never ones in already-crowded areas, so recovery flows toward the empty parts of a map. Every correction stays inside the limits below, healthy groups are left completely alone, and the game engine still decides every spawn.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_enabled">
        <text>Enable Smart Balance</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_enabled_desc">
        <text>Master toggle for Smart Balance. When off, no census and no cooldown corrections.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_advances">
        <text>Correction steps to floor</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_advances_desc">
        <text>How many census passes it takes to carry one smart terrain from full cooldown to the floor while its group stays depleted (a pass covers all tracked squads, several minutes of real time). Delays use the same step size in the opposite direction. At 1, a single pass pushes a smart all the way. At 4 (default), four passes step it through at 25% per pass. At 8, eight passes at 12.5% per pass. Higher values correct more gradually.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_min_minutes">
        <text>Minimum cooldown remaining (game minutes)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_min_minutes_desc">
        <text>The minimum cooldown that must always remain on a smart terrain after Smart Balance applies an acceleration, in game-minutes. The engine ages the final wait out on its own clock and fires the respawn from there. A smart already within this margin of firing naturally is skipped. Default 120 minutes (two game-hours). Raise to leave more delay between depletion and refill; lower for snappier turnover.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_max_minutes">
        <text>Maximum cooldown remaining (game minutes)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_max_minutes_desc">
        <text>The ceiling on remaining cooldown after Smart Balance applies a delay, in game-minutes. Delays stop once a smart terrain's remaining wait reaches this ceiling, even when the installed respawn cooldown is longer. When the respawn cooldown is at or below the ceiling, one full vanilla cooldown stays the bound. Raise to idle overgrown groups longer; lower to keep recovery moving everywhere.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_refill">
        <text>Refill depleted squads</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_refill_desc">
        <text>Gradually restores members to squads that dropped below their own minimum size, one member per squad per census pass, while their group is below the map's declared population. Runs only on squads far from the player, skips crowded areas, and never adds beyond the squad's own configured range. Fixed-roster and story squads are untouched. Overgrown groups are handled by cooldown delays alone.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== DEVELOPMENT TAB ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_desc">
        <text>Diagnostic tools for tuning and troubleshooting. Raise log level for structured tracing of every census pass, capacity model, advance, delay, and squad refill to alifebalance.log (small performance cost at DEBUG).</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_btn_reset_all">
        <text>Reset to defaults</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_btn_reset_all_desc">
        <text>Restore all AlifeBalance MCM settings to factory defaults. Use after upgrading from a version with different MCM structure (the old settings remain as orphaned keys in the MCM storage file but no longer apply).</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_reset_warning">
        <text>Warning: save or discard pending MCM changes first; otherwise they override the reset on the next Accept.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Development - Logging -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_hdr_logging">
        <text>Logging</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_log_level">
        <text>Log level</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_log_level_desc">
        <text>Controls verbosity of alifebalance.log. ERROR logs crashes only. WARN adds unexpected conditions. INFO adds startup, configuration, and reset events. DEBUG traces every census pass, capacity model, advance, delay, squad refill, and per-pass summary. Default WARN is silent in normal play; DEBUG is for tuning or bug reports.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_error">
        <text>Error</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_warn">
        <text>Warn</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_info">
        <text>Info</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_debug">
        <text>Debug</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Development - Diagnostics -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_hdr_diagnostics">
        <text>Diagnostics</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_show_markers">
        <text>Show map markers</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_show_markers_desc">
        <text>Drops a green PDA map marker on every smart terrain that receives a cooldown advance or delay. The marker lingers for five real-time minutes and then clears itself. Right-click any marker to teleport to that smart or display its full correction history. Independent of log level, so you can run with markers on and logging off for a clean session view.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Map menu actions -->
    <string id="st_ab_smart_map_teleport_to">
        <text>Teleport to</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_ab_smart_map_show_stats">
        <text>Show stats for</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
