<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
    <!-- ==================== MAIN MENU ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_menu_ab">
        <text>AlifeBalance</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== TAB NAMES ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_menu_smart_balance">
        <text>Smart Balance</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_menu_development">
        <text>Development</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== SHARED ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_title">
        <text>AlifeBalance</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== SMART BALANCE TAB ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_desc">
        <text>Smart Balance dynamically adapts respawn to where combat actually happens. It counts deaths per region and faction, then advances the cooldown at the matching smart farthest from you so refills land off-screen. The engine still owns every spawn. Smart Balance only nudges a timestamp it was going to read anyway. Without it, vanilla's global fixed cooldown leaves fight regions empty while quiet maps overcrowd.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_enabled">
        <text>Enable Smart Balance</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_enabled_desc">
        <text>Master toggle for Smart Balance. When off, no death tracking and no cooldown advances.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_advances">
        <text>Advances to floor</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_advances_desc">
        <text>How many combat bursts it takes to fully accelerate one smart terrain from full cooldown to the floor. A burst is one squad's worth of deaths in the affected faction (set automatically from the largest possible squad size for that faction). At 1, a single burst pushes a smart all the way to the floor. At 4 (default), four bursts step it through at 25% per burst. At 8, eight bursts at 12.5% per burst. Higher values pace acceleration across longer combat so a single firefight does not flush everything at once.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_min_minutes">
        <text>Minimum cooldown remaining (game minutes)</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_smart_balance_min_minutes_desc">
        <text>The minimum cooldown that must always remain on a smart terrain after Smart Balance applies an acceleration, in game-minutes. The engine ages the final wait out on its own clock and fires the respawn from there. A smart already within this margin of firing naturally is skipped. Default 120 minutes (two game-hours). Raise to leave more delay between combat and refill; lower for snappier turnover.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- ==================== DEVELOPMENT TAB ==================== -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_desc">
        <text>Diagnostic tools for tuning and troubleshooting. Raise log level for structured tracing of every death, advance, and eligibility scan to alifebalance.log (small performance cost at DEBUG).</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_btn_reset_all">
        <text>Reset to defaults</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_btn_reset_all_desc">
        <text>Restore all AlifeBalance MCM settings to factory defaults. Use after upgrading from a version with different MCM structure (the old settings remain as orphaned keys in the MCM storage file but no longer apply).</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_reset_warning">
        <text>Warning: save or discard pending MCM changes first; otherwise they override the reset on the next Accept.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Development - Logging -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_hdr_logging">
        <text>Logging</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_log_level">
        <text>Log level</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_log_level_desc">
        <text>Controls verbosity of alifebalance.log. ERROR logs crashes only. WARN adds unexpected conditions. INFO adds startup, configuration, and reset events. DEBUG traces every death, advance, eligibility scan, gate outcome, and per-cycle summary. Default WARN is silent in normal play; DEBUG is for tuning or bug reports.</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_error">
        <text>Error</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_warn">
        <text>Warn</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_info">
        <text>Info</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ab_development_log_level_lst_debug">
        <text>Debug</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Development - Diagnostics -->
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_hdr_diagnostics">
        <text>Diagnostics</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_show_markers">
        <text>Show map markers</text>
    </string>
    <string id="ui_mcm_ab_development_show_markers_desc">
        <text>Drops a green PDA map marker on every smart terrain that receives a cooldown advance. The marker lingers for five real-time minutes and then clears itself. Right-click any marker to teleport to that smart or display its full advance history. Independent of log level, so you can run with markers on and logging off for a clean session view.</text>
    </string>

    <!-- Map menu actions -->
    <string id="st_ab_smart_map_teleport_to">
        <text>Teleport to</text>
    </string>
    <string id="st_ab_smart_map_show_stats">
        <text>Show stats for</text>
    </string>
</string_table>
